# JINHONG "JIN" CHOI

Corvallis, OR | 1+1-617-803-3057 | jinhong.choi@gmail.com | in jinhongchoi | in jinhongchoi

## SUMMARY

Experienced in researching cyber-physical systems, particularly drones, with a strong background in software development in C on drone platforms. Holding a solid foundation in computer science and mechanical engineering, I focus on developing software and applying algorithms for embedded systems, IoT devices, and autonomous vehicles.

#### EDUCATION

**Oregon State University** Corvallis, OR

Master of Science, Electrical Engineering and Computer Science (GPA: 3.83/4.00)

April 2019 - August 2024

September 2010 – January 2014

A Decentralized Algorithm for Detecting a Global Predicate in Real-time for a Swarm of Drones

Massachusetts Institute of Technology Completed 72 credits towards a MS in Mechanical Engineering (GPA: 4.8/5.0) Cambridge, MA

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology

Daejeon, South Korea Bachelors of Science, Mechanical Engineering, summa cum laude (GPA: 3.91/4.00) January 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

**Oregon State University** 

Corvallis, OR

Graduate Research Assistant

June 2020 - Present

- Three projects regarding security and safety for Unmanned Aerial System (UAS), funded by Federal Aviation Administration (FAA): A38-UAS Cyber Security and Safety Literature Review, A58-Illustrate the Need for Cybersecurity Oversight and Risk Management, A51-Best Engineering Practices for Automated Systems
- A project funded by OMIC: Enhancing human-robot teaming via improvements to nonverbal robot expression

Graduate Teaching Assistant: Operating Systems II, Algorithms and Data Structures

Hyundai KEFICO Gunpo, South Korea

Researcher, Prototype Development Team

February 2016 – February 2019

• Prototyped gasoline fuel injectors under development, specialized to control femto-second laser systems for precise drilling of fuel spray holes

LX Hausys (previously LG Hausys)

Seoul, South Korea

Consultant

February 2010 - June 2010

• Consulted on optically transparent adhesive used in touchscreens for mobile devices

Hantouch

Researcher (alternative to mandatory military service)

Seoul, South Korea

February 2007 - May 2009

• Developed resistive touchscreens integrated with mobile devices, securing three patents in South Korea (Application Numbers: 10-2008-0070246, 10-2008-0056270, 10-2007-0113098)

#### SKILLS

**Programming Languages** C/C++, Python, Julia, Haskell

Languages English (Professional), Korean (Native)

**Others** Git, ROS, FreeRTOS, Unix/Linux, AutoCAD, MATLAB

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Unmesh Uttam Patil, Jinhong Choi, and Houssam Abbas. "OUT-HERD: Opportunistic UAV Takeover for Herding Malfunctioning Drones". In: 2024 IEEE 27th International Conference on Intelligent Transportation Systems (ITSC). 2024.
- Jinhong Choi and Yeongjin Jang. "A Survey on Sensor False Data Injection Attacks and Countermeasures in Cyber-Physical and Embedded Systems". In: Information Security Applications: 23rd International Conference, WISA 2022, Revised Selected Papers. Springer. 2022.

Last updated: July 2024